<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-06-23T00:47:18-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Evolve or Die</title><subtitle>Mainly about technology, management, ideas</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Thoughts on Ethics for Data Science</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/markdown/2021/06/23/thoughts-on-ethics-for-data-science.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Thoughts on Ethics for Data Science" /><published>2021-06-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-06-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/markdown/2021/06/23/thoughts-on-ethics-for-data-science</id><author><name></name></author><category term="markdown" /><summary type="html">Recently, I am taking a online deep learning course on fast.ai. The lesson 3 of the course is focusing on data ethics. The lecturer, Rachel Thomas, touches a few points that I echo back. Around 1:52:50, there is a short discussion Q: Maybe the best way to incentivize ethical behavior it to tie financial or reputational risk to good behavior. In some ways, similar to how companies are now investing in cybersecurity because they don’t want to be the next Equifax. Can grassroots compaigns help in better ethical behaviors with regards to the use of AI? Rachel Thomas: …I think it’s hard for people to make the case to their boses of why they should be investing in cybersecurity. Particularly because cybersecurity is something that when it’s working well, you don’t notice it. …</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Think Again - Apple anecdote and Mount Stupid</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/markdown/2021/06/21/think-again-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Think Again - Apple anecdote and Mount Stupid" /><published>2021-06-21T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-06-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/markdown/2021/06/21/think-again-2</id><author><name></name></author><category term="markdown" /><summary type="html">The legend of Apple’s renaissance revolves around the lone genius of Steve Jobs. It was his conviction and clarity of vision, the story goes, that gave birth to the iPhone. Th reality is that he was dead-set against the mobile phone category. His employees had the vision for it, and it was their ability to change his mind that really revived Apple. Although Jobs knew how to “think different”, it was his team that did much of the rethinking.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Think Again - mentality and “I’m not biased” bias</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/markdown/2021/06/20/think-again-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Think Again - mentality and “I’m not biased” bias" /><published>2021-06-20T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-06-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/markdown/2021/06/20/think-again-1</id><author><name></name></author><category term="markdown" /><summary type="html">Think again can help you generate new solutions to old problems and revisit old solutions to new problems. It’s a path to learning more from the poeple around you and living with fewer regrets. A hallmark of wisdom is knowing when it’s time to abandon some of your most treasured tools and some of the most cherished parts of your identity.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why I start blogging and why the blog name is “Evolve Or Die”</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/markdown/2021/06/14/why-i-start-blogging.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why I start blogging and why the blog name is “Evolve Or Die”" /><published>2021-06-14T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-06-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/markdown/2021/06/14/why-i-start-blogging</id><author><name></name></author><category term="markdown" /><summary type="html">Evolve Or Die Principles by Ray Dalio:  Evolve or die. This evolutionary cycle is not just for people but for countries, companies, economies—for everything. And it is naturally self-correcting as a whole, though not necessarily for its parts. For example, if there is too much supply and waste in a market, prices will go down, companies will go out of business, and capacity will be reduced until the supply falls in line with the demand, at which time the cycle will start to move in the opposite direction. Similarly, if an economy turns bad enough, those responsible for running it will make the political and policy changes that are needed or they will not survive, making room for their replacements to come along. These cycles are continuous and play out in logical ways and they tend to be self-reinforcing.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Thoughts about tenacity and deep learning</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/markdown/2021/06/14/thoughts-on-tenacity-and-deep-learning.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Thoughts about tenacity and deep learning" /><published>2021-06-14T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-06-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/markdown/2021/06/14/thoughts-on-tenacity-and-deep-learning</id><author><name></name></author><category term="markdown" /><summary type="html">The following are quoted from a fast.ai notebook (04_mnist_basics) discussing Tenacity and Deep Learning. I want to share some reflection on this “touching” anecdote.</summary></entry></feed>