<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-01-15T13:16:36-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Evolve or Die</title><subtitle>Mainly about technology, management, ideas</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Wherever you go three you are - 2</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/personal_development/reading_notes/2022/01/15/wherever-you-go-there-you-are-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wherever you go three you are - 2" /><published>2022-01-15T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-01-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/personal_development/reading_notes/2022/01/15/wherever-you-go-there-you-are-2</id><author><name></name></author><category term="personal_development" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“Effortless activity happens at moments in dance and in sports at the highest levels of performance; when it does, it takes everybody’s breath away. But it also happens in every area of human activity, from painting to car repair to parenting. Years of practice and experience combine on some occasions, giving rise to a new capacity to let execution unfold beyond technique, beyond exertion, beyond thinking. Action then becomes a pure expression of art, of being, of letting go of all doing—a merging of mind and body in motion. We thrill in watching a superb performance, whether athletic or artistic, because it allows us to participate in the magic of true mastery, to be uplifted, if only briefly, and perhaps to share in the intention that each of us, in our own way, might touch such moments of grace and harmony in the living of our own lives.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Wherever you go three you are - 1</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/personal_development/reading_notes/2022/01/15/wherever-you-go-there-you-are-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wherever you go three you are - 1" /><published>2022-01-15T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-01-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/personal_development/reading_notes/2022/01/15/wherever-you-go-there-you-are-1</id><author><name></name></author><category term="personal_development" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">开始重读Wherever you go there you are。 “By lost, I mean that we momentarily lose touch with ourselves and with the full extent of our possibilities. Instead, we fall into a robotlike way of seeing and thinking and doing. In those moments, we break contact with what is deepest in ourselves and affords us perhaps our greatest opportunities for creativity, learning, and growing. If we are not careful, those clouded moments can stretch out and become most of our lives.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The evolution of cooperation - 10</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/personal_development/reading_notes/2022/01/15/the-evolution-of-cooperation-10.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The evolution of cooperation - 10" /><published>2022-01-15T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-01-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/personal_development/reading_notes/2022/01/15/the-evolution-of-cooperation-10</id><author><name></name></author><category term="personal_development" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“A common reaction of someone caught in a Prisoner’s Dilemma is that “there ought to be a law against this sort of thing.” In fact, getting out of Prisoner’s Dilemmas is one of the primary functions of government: to make sure that when individuals do not have private incentives to cooperate, they will be required to do the socially useful thing anyway. Laws are passed to cause people to pay their taxes, not to steal, and to honor contracts with strangers. Each of these activities could be regarded as a giant Prisoner’s Dilemma game with many players. No one wants to pay taxes because the benefits are so diffuse and the costs are so direct. But everyone may be better off if each person has to pay so that each can share the benefits of schools, roads, and other collective goods (Schelling 1973). This is a major part of what Rousseau meant when he said that government’s role is to make sure that each citizen “will be forced to be free”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The evolution of cooperation - 9</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/personal_development/reading_notes/2022/01/07/the-evolution-of-cooperation-9.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The evolution of cooperation - 9" /><published>2022-01-07T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-01-07T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/personal_development/reading_notes/2022/01/07/the-evolution-of-cooperation-9</id><author><name></name></author><category term="personal_development" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“There is yet a third way in which some of the tournament rules are too clever: they employ a probabilistic strategy that is so complex that it cannot be distinguished by the other strategies from a purely random choice. In other words, too much complexity can appear to be total chaos. If you are using a strategy which appears random, then you also appear unresponsive to the other player. If you are unresponsive, then the other player has no incentive to cooperate with you. So being so complex as to be incomprehensible is very dangerous.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The evolution of cooperation - 8</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/personal_development/reading_notes/2022/01/07/the-evolution-of-cooperation-8.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The evolution of cooperation - 8" /><published>2022-01-07T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-01-07T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/personal_development/reading_notes/2022/01/07/the-evolution-of-cooperation-8</id><author><name></name></author><category term="personal_development" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“When the future of the interaction is not important enough relative to immediate gains from defection, then simply waiting for the other to defect is not such a good idea. It is important to bear in mind that TIT FOR TAT is a stable strategy only when the discount parameter, w, is high enough relative to the payoff parameters, R, S, T, and P. In particular, proposition 2 shows that if the discount parameter is not high enough and the other player is using TIT FOR TAT, a player is better off alternating defection and cooperation, or even always defecting. Therefore, if the other player is not likely to be seen again, defecting right away is better than being nice.”</summary></entry></feed>