<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-02-19T18:03:02-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Evolve or Die</title><subtitle>Mainly about technology, management, ideas</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The First 90 days, Updated and Expanded - Proven strategies for getting up to speed faster and smarter - 5</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/leadership/reading_notes/2022/02/19/the-first-90-days-5.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The First 90 days, Updated and Expanded - Proven strategies for getting up to speed faster and smarter - 5" /><published>2022-02-19T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-02-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/leadership/reading_notes/2022/02/19/the-first-90-days-5</id><author><name></name></author><category term="leadership" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“Julia failed because she did not make the leap from being a strong functional performer to taking on a cross-functional, project-leadership role. She failed to grasp that the strengths that had made her successful in marketing could be liabilities in a role that required her to lead without direct authority or superior expertise. She kept doing what she knew how to do, making her feel confident and in control. The result, of course, was the opposite. By not letting go of the past and not fully embracing her new role, she squandered a big opportunity to rise in the organization.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The First 90 days, Updated and Expanded - Proven strategies for getting up to speed faster and smarter - 4</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/leadership/reading_notes/2022/02/19/the-first-90-days-4.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The First 90 days, Updated and Expanded - Proven strategies for getting up to speed faster and smarter - 4" /><published>2022-02-19T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-02-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/leadership/reading_notes/2022/02/19/the-first-90-days-4</id><author><name></name></author><category term="leadership" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“Negotiate success. Because no other single relationship is more important, you need to figure out how to build a productive working relationship with your new boss (or bosses) and manage her expectations. This means carefully planning for a series of critical conversations about the situation, expectations, working style, resources, and your personal development. Crucially, it means developing and gaining consensus on your 90-day plan.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The First 90 days, Updated and Expanded - Proven strategies for getting up to speed faster and smarter - 3</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/leadership/reading_notes/2022/02/10/the-first-90-days-3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The First 90 days, Updated and Expanded - Proven strategies for getting up to speed faster and smarter - 3" /><published>2022-02-10T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-02-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/leadership/reading_notes/2022/02/10/the-first-90-days-3</id><author><name></name></author><category term="leadership" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“Engaging in the wrong type of learning. You spend too much time focused on learning about the technical part of the business and not enough about the cultural and political dimensions of your new role. You don’t build the cultural insight, relationships, and information conduits you need if you’re to understand what is really going on.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The First 90 days, Updated and Expanded - Proven strategies for getting up to speed faster and smarter - 2</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/leadership/reading_notes/2022/02/09/the-first-90-days-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The First 90 days, Updated and Expanded - Proven strategies for getting up to speed faster and smarter - 2" /><published>2022-02-09T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-02-09T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/leadership/reading_notes/2022/02/09/the-first-90-days-2</id><author><name></name></author><category term="leadership" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“Why are transitions critical? When I surveyed more than thirteen hundred senior HR leaders, almost 90 percent agreed that “transitions into new roles are the most challenging times in the professional lives of leaders.”1 And nearly three-quarters agreed that “success or failure during the first few months is a strong predictor of overall success or failure in the job.” So even though a bad transition does not necessarily doom you to failure, it makes success a lot less likely. The good news on transitions is that they give you a chance to start afresh and make needed changes in an organization. But transitions are also periods of acute vulnerability, because you lack established working relationships and a detailed understanding of your new role. You’re managing under a microscope, subject to a high degree of scrutiny as people around you strive to figure out who you are and what you represent as a leader. Opinions of your effectiveness begin to form surprisingly quickly, and, once formed, they’re very hard to change. If you’re successful in building credibility and securing early wins, the momentum likely will propel you through the rest of your tenure. But if you dig yourself into a hole early on, you will face an uphill battle from that point forward.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The First 90 days, Updated and Expanded - Proven strategies for getting up to speed faster and smarter - 1</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/leadership/reading_notes/2022/02/08/the-first-90-days-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The First 90 days, Updated and Expanded - Proven strategies for getting up to speed faster and smarter - 1" /><published>2022-02-08T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-02-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/leadership/reading_notes/2022/02/08/the-first-90-days-1</id><author><name></name></author><category term="leadership" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“The point of the expectations conversation is for you and your boss to clarify and align your expectations about the future. You need to agree on short- and medium-term goals and on timing. Critically, you need to agree on how your boss will measure progress. What will constitute success, for your boss and for you? When does your boss expect to see results? How will you measure success? Over what time frame? If you succeed, what is next? If you don’t manage expectations, they will manage you.”</summary></entry></feed>