<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-05-16T00:14:59-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Evolve or Die</title><subtitle>Mainly about technology, management, ideas</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The manager’s path - 17</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/15/the-manager-path-17.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The manager’s path - 17" /><published>2022-05-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-05-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/15/the-manager-path-17</id><author><name></name></author><category term="management" /><category term="leadership" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“I have some quibbles with that. Employees with obligations that take them out of the office at a strict time every day are no more or less engaged than those who are willing to stand around and chat. The larger point, however, is still a good one. Most gelled teams have a sense of camaraderie that makes them joke together, get coffee, share lunch, and feel friendly toward one another. They may have obligations they respect, and passions outside of work, but they don’t view their team as something they’re eager to escape every day. The real goal here is psychological safety—that is, a team whose members are willing to take risks and make mistakes in front of one another. This is the underpinning of a successful team. The work of gelling a team begins by creating the friendliness that leads to psychological safety. You can encourage this by taking the time to get to know people as human beings and asking them about their extracurricular lives and interests. Let them share what they feel comfortable sharing. Ask how their child’s birthday party went, how their ski trip was, how their marathon training is going. This is more than empty small talk; it fosters relatedness, the sense of people as individuals and not just anonymous cogs.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The manager’s path - 16</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/15/the-manager-path-16.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The manager’s path - 16" /><published>2022-05-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-05-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/15/the-manager-path-16</id><author><name></name></author><category term="management" /><category term="leadership" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“Don’t rely exclusively on consensus or voting. Consensus can appear morally authoritative, but that assumes that everyone involved in the voting process is impartial, has an equal stake in the various outcomes, and has equal knowledge of the context. These conditions are rarely met on teams where each person has different levels of expertise and different roles”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Radical Candor - 1</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/15/radical-candor-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Radical Candor - 1" /><published>2022-05-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-05-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/15/radical-candor-1</id><author><name></name></author><category term="management" /><category term="leadership" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“Then a leader at Apple pointed out to me that all teams need stability as well as growth to function properly; nothing works well if everyone is gunning for the next promotion. She called the people on her team who got exceptional results but who were on a more gradual growth trajectory “rock stars” because they were like the Rock of Gibraltar on her team. These people loved their work and were world-class at it, but they didn’t want her job or to be Steve Jobs. They were happy where they were. The people who were on a steeper growth trajectory—the ones who’d go crazy if they were still doing the same job in a year—she called “superstars.” They were the source of growth on any team. She was explicit about needing a balance of both”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The manager’s path - 15</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/08/the-manager-path-15.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The manager’s path - 15" /><published>2022-05-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-05-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/08/the-manager-path-15</id><author><name></name></author><category term="management" /><category term="leadership" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“So, yes, shielding your teams from distraction is important. Or, to put it another way, helping them understand the key important goals and focusing them on those goals is important. However, it’s unrealistic to expect that you can or should shield your team from everything. Sometimes it’s appropriate to let some of the stress through to the team. The goal is not to stress them out, but to help them get context into what they’re dealing with. The extreme shielders think they can best focus and motivate their teams by giving clear goals. But humans usually need some sort of context into why these goals have been set, and thereby into what problems they’re working to solve. If you’re going to have operational issues in November if a particular system isn’t up and running, your team deserves to understand that consequence. Appropriate context is what helps teams make good decisions about how and where to focus their energy. As the manager, it’s not your job to make all of those decisions by yourself.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The manager’s path - 14</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/08/the-manager-path-14.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The manager’s path - 14" /><published>2022-05-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-05-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/08/the-manager-path-14</id><author><name></name></author><category term="management" /><category term="leadership" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“The negative person is easier to deal with than the brilliant jerk. Make it clear to him that the behavior has to change, bring clear examples, and provide corrective feedback quickly after things happen. Sometimes the negative person is just unhappy and the best thing to do is to help him leave the team on good terms; you must be prepared for this outcome. Other times, the person has no idea about the impact he’s having on the team, and a quick chat will be all that’s needed to curtail the incidents. Be careful that vocally negative people don’t stay in that mindset on your team for long. The kind of toxic drama that is created by these energy vampires is hard for even the best manager to combat. The best defense is a good offense in this case, and quick action is essential.”</summary></entry></feed>