<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-08-24T23:44:54-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Evolve or Die</title><subtitle>Mainly about technology, management, ideas</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The Psychology of Money - Timeless lesson of Wealth, Greed, and Happiness - When you’ll believe anything</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/reading_notes/2021/08/23/the-psychology-of-money-17.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Psychology of Money - Timeless lesson of Wealth, Greed, and Happiness - When you’ll believe anything" /><published>2021-08-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-08-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/reading_notes/2021/08/23/the-psychology-of-money-17</id><author><name></name></author><category term="investment" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“The more you want something to be true, the more likely you are to believe a story that overestimates the odds of it being true” “Why do people listen to TV investment commentary that has little track record of success? Partly because the stakes are so high in investing.” “Consider that 85% of active mutual funds underperformed their benchmark over the 10 years ending 2018.⁶⁵ That figure has been fairly stable for generations. You would think an industry with such poor performance would be a niche service and have a hard time staying in business. But there’s almost five trillion dollars invested in these funds.⁶”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Psychology of Money - Timeless lesson of Wealth, Greed, and Happiness - The Seduction of Pessimism</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/reading_notes/2021/08/23/the-psychology-of-money-16.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Psychology of Money - Timeless lesson of Wealth, Greed, and Happiness - The Seduction of Pessimism" /><published>2021-08-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-08-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/reading_notes/2021/08/23/the-psychology-of-money-16</id><author><name></name></author><category term="investment" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“Real optimists don’t believe that everything will be great. That’s complacency. Optimism is a belief that the odds of a good outcome are in your favor over time, even when there will be setbacks along the way. The simple idea that most people wake up in the morning trying to make things a little better and more productive than wake up looking to cause trouble is the foundation of optimism. It’s not complicated. It’s not guaranteed, either. It’s just the most reasonable bet for most people, most of the time. The late statistician Hans Rosling put it differently: “I am not an optimist. I am a very serious possibilist.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Psychology of Money - Timeless lesson of Wealth, Greed, and Happiness - You’ll change</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/reading_notes/2021/08/23/the-psychology-of-money-13.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Psychology of Money - Timeless lesson of Wealth, Greed, and Happiness - You’ll change" /><published>2021-08-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-08-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/reading_notes/2021/08/23/the-psychology-of-money-13</id><author><name></name></author><category term="investment" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“The End of History Illusion is what psychologists call the tendency for people to be keenly aware of how much they’ve changed in the past, but to underestimate how much their personalities, desires, and goals are likely to change in the future. ” “All of us,” he said, “are walking around with an illusion—an illusion that history, our personal history, has just come to an end, that we have just recently become the people that we were always meant to be and will be for the rest of our lives.” We tend to never learn this lesson. Gilbert’s research shows people from age 18 to 68 underestimate how much they will change in the future.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Psychology of Money - Timeless lesson of Wealth, Greed, and Happiness - Nothing’s free</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/reading_notes/2021/08/23/the-psychology-of-money-14.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Psychology of Money - Timeless lesson of Wealth, Greed, and Happiness - Nothing’s free" /><published>2021-08-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-08-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/reading_notes/2021/08/23/the-psychology-of-money-14</id><author><name></name></author><category term="investment" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“Like everything else worthwhile, successful investing demands a price. But its currency is not dollars and cents. It’s volatility, fear, doubt, uncertainty, and regret—all of which are easy to overlook until you’re dealing with them in real time.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Psychology of Money - Timeless lesson of Wealth, Greed, and Happiness - You and me</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/reading_notes/2021/08/23/the-psychology-of-money-15.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Psychology of Money - Timeless lesson of Wealth, Greed, and Happiness - You and me" /><published>2021-08-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-08-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/reading_notes/2021/08/23/the-psychology-of-money-15</id><author><name></name></author><category term="investment" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“Investors often innocently take cues from other investors who are playing a different game than they are.” “When investors have different goals and time horizons—and they do in every asset class—prices that look ridiculous to one person can make sense to another, because the factors those investors pay attention to are different.” “A takeaway here is that few things matter more with money than understanding your own time horizon and not being persuaded by the actions and behaviors of people playing different games than you are.”</summary></entry></feed>