<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-12-29T22:57:07-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Evolve or Die</title><subtitle>Mainly about technology, management, ideas</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The evolution of cooperation - 3</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/personal_development/reading_notes/2021/12/24/the-evolution-of-cooperation-3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The evolution of cooperation - 3" /><published>2021-12-24T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-12-24T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/personal_development/reading_notes/2021/12/24/the-evolution-of-cooperation-3</id><author><name></name></author><category term="personal_development" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“From the participant’s point of view, the object is to do as well as possible, regardless of how well the other player does. Based upon the tournament results and the formal propositions, four simple suggestions are offered for individual choice: do not be envious of the other player’s success; do not be the first to defect; reciprocate both cooperation and defection; and do not be too clever.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The evolution of cooperation - 2</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/personal_development/reading_notes/2021/12/24/the-evolution-of-cooperation-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The evolution of cooperation - 2" /><published>2021-12-24T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-12-24T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/personal_development/reading_notes/2021/12/24/the-evolution-of-cooperation-2</id><author><name></name></author><category term="personal_development" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“In this book I will examine interactions between just two players at a time. A single player may be interacting with many others, but the player is assumed to be interacting with them one at a time.3 The player is also assumed to recognize another player and to remember how the two of them have interacted so far. This ability to recognize and remember allows the history of the particular interaction to be taken into account by a player’s strategy. A variety of ways to resolve the Prisoner’s Dilemma have been developed. Each involves allowing some additional activity that alters the strategic interaction in such a way as to fundamentally change the nature of the problem. The original problem remains, however, because there are many situations in which these remedies are not available. Therefore, the problem will be considered in its fundamental form, without these alterations. There is no mechanism available to the players to make enforceable threats or commitments (Schelling 1960). Since the players cannot commit themselves to a particular strategy, each must take into account all possible strategies that might be used by the other player. Moreover the players have all possible strategies available to themselves There is no way to be sure what the other player will do on a given move. This eliminates the possibility of rne-tagame analysis (Howard 1971) which allows such options as “make the same choice as the other is about to make.” It also eliminates the possibility of reliable reputations such as might be based on watching the other player interact with third parties. Thus the only information available to the players about each other is the history of their interaction so far. There is no way to eliminate the other player or run away from the interaction. Therefore each player retains the ability to cooperate or defect on each move. There is no way to change the other player’s payoffs. The payoffs already include whatever consideration each player has for the interests of the other (Taylor 1976, pp. 69-73).”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The evolution of cooperation - 1</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/personal_development/reading_notes/2021/12/24/the-evolution-of-cooperation-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The evolution of cooperation - 1" /><published>2021-12-24T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-12-24T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/personal_development/reading_notes/2021/12/24/the-evolution-of-cooperation-1</id><author><name></name></author><category term="personal_development" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“We all know that people are not angels, and that they tend to look after themselves and their own first. Yet we also know that cooperation does occur and that our civilization is based upon it. But, in situations where each individual has an incentive to be selfish, how can cooperation ever develop?” “The approach of this book is to investigate how individuals pursuing their own interests will act, followed by an analysis of what effects this will have for the system as a whole. Put another way, the approach is to make some assumptions about individual motives and then deduce consequences for the behavior of the entire system (Schelling 1978). The case of the U.S. Senate is a good example, but the same style of reasoning can be applied to other settings.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Big Debt Crisis - 12</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/reading_notes/2021/12/12/big-debt-crisis-12.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Big Debt Crisis - 12" /><published>2021-12-12T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-12-12T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/reading_notes/2021/12/12/big-debt-crisis-12</id><author><name></name></author><category term="investment" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">Asset/currency holders typically worry that policy makers will impose restrictions on their ability to get their money out of the country, which encourages them to get their money out while they still can, which further increases the balance of payments problem. Policy makers worry about capital outflows and the possibility of a currency collapse. As the balance of payments deteriorate, the central bank’s job becomes more difficult—i.e., it gets less economic growth per unit of inflation because the negative flows lead the currency to depreciate, interest rates to rise, and/or reserves to decline, depending on how the central bank chooses to handle it.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Big Debt Crisis - 11</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/reading_notes/2021/12/12/big-debt-crisis-11.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Big Debt Crisis - 11" /><published>2021-12-12T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-12-12T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/reading_notes/2021/12/12/big-debt-crisis-11</id><author><name></name></author><category term="investment" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">As the bubble emerges, there are fewer productive investments, and at the same time there is more capital going after them. The fundamental attractiveness of the country that sparked the boom fades, in part because the rising currency is eroding the country’s competitiveness.</summary></entry></feed>