<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-09-19T17:03:34-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Evolve or Die</title><subtitle>Mainly about technology, management, ideas</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Early Retirement Extreme - A philosophical and practical guide to financial independence - 5</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/fire/reading_notes/2021/09/19/early-retirement-extreme-5.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Early Retirement Extreme - A philosophical and practical guide to financial independence - 5" /><published>2021-09-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-09-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/fire/reading_notes/2021/09/19/early-retirement-extreme-5</id><author><name></name></author><category term="investment" /><category term="FIRE" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“The design presented in the rest of the book rests on three pillars. First, reduce waste and increase efficiency. Many of these expenses are eliminated by only owning what is actually used, and maintaining what is bought.” “Second, having significantly reduced expenses, invest the difference in businesses.” “Third, find something meaningful to do instead of work. If your work is really meaningful to you, you can keep working, knowing that you are living a less wasteful existence and that you have the financial security to leave your job at any time. ”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Early Retirement Extreme - A philosophical and practical guide to financial independence - 4</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/fire/reading_notes/2021/09/19/early-retirement-extreme-4.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Early Retirement Extreme - A philosophical and practical guide to financial independence - 4" /><published>2021-09-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-09-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/fire/reading_notes/2021/09/19/early-retirement-extreme-4</id><author><name></name></author><category term="investment" /><category term="FIRE" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“A so-called career provides a similar sorting mechanism. People frequently talk about climbing the corporate ladder. However, a ladder implies that if one climbs hard enough, one eventually will get to the top. In reality, it’s more like a corporate pyramid. Not only does one have to climb hard; one also has to beat the other climbers as the pyramid gets narrower and narrower.” “Here, one solution is to moderate one’s career ambitions. After all, realizing at an early point that going all the way not only depends on skills, but also requires 100% dedication, reading time, and possibly some ethical compromises, one can aid in the sorting process by consciously seeking positions suitable to one’s more moderate aims and avoiding unnecessary competition.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Early Retirement Extreme - A philosophical and practical guide to financial independence - 2</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/fire/reading_notes/2021/09/19/early-retirement-extreme-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Early Retirement Extreme - A philosophical and practical guide to financial independence - 2" /><published>2021-09-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-09-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/fire/reading_notes/2021/09/19/early-retirement-extreme-2</id><author><name></name></author><category term="investment" /><category term="FIRE" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“To paraphrase Einstein, you can’t solve your problems with the same mindset that created them. To live as a free person, following lists of easy, repetitive things, possibly in return for some reward, is exactly what should be avoided. Instead, it’s necessary to understand how the world works and how people have been specialized to the point of general incompetence, like ants, which only know how to do one job, but do it very well; this is not human nature. To live well, one must go beyond lists and start thinking creatively about solving problems.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Early Retirement Extreme - A philosophical and practical guide to financial independence - 3</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/fire/reading_notes/2021/09/19/early-retirement-extreme-3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Early Retirement Extreme - A philosophical and practical guide to financial independence - 3" /><published>2021-09-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-09-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/fire/reading_notes/2021/09/19/early-retirement-extreme-3</id><author><name></name></author><category term="investment" /><category term="FIRE" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“We create problems, spend the next day solving them, and then claim we have made progress. We’re even following Keynes’ suggestion quite literally when we dig resources out of the ground, fashion them into consumer objects, temporarily store them in our homes, rarely use them, and eventually replace them with a new and bigger model, while sending the old and likely still functional object to a landfill–back in the ground”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Early Retirement Extreme - A philosophical and practical guide to financial independence - 1</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/fire/reading_notes/2021/09/18/early-retirement-extreme-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Early Retirement Extreme - A philosophical and practical guide to financial independence - 1" /><published>2021-09-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-09-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/fire/reading_notes/2021/09/18/early-retirement-extreme-1</id><author><name></name></author><category term="investment" /><category term="FIRE" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">这本书是2010年写的，Jacob Lund Fisker是比较早期Financial Independence Retire Early (FIRE)的倡导者。FIRE到后面也分成了LEAN FIRE, FAT FIRE等等很多种，而这本书主要是偏向于LEAN FIRE，大致就是尽可能削减生活成本，用很短的时间实现财务自由（作者用了5年）。作者在书中主要说了一种文艺复兴的人类，学习很多技能，尽可能自己做事，从各方面降低生活成本，避免消费主义陷阱，也给出了挺多实打实的计算（虽然不是重点）。书本身比较偏向于哲学而不是方法论，作者相信每个人有每个人自己的FIRE，而过多描述他自己的FIRE本身意义不大，授人以鱼不如授人以渔。 “At some point, the teacher introduced tests and grades. Test-taking became the primary objective; learning secondary. We had the option to quickly forget what we had spent the past year learning after the test was done. In other words, we were being taught to be “flexible.” Later, there were job fairs and educational fairs telling us how to write résumés and how to interview so we could get jobs. Yet, I never learned why the world worked the way it did, and in retrospect, I think nobody ever even asked the question. Everybody always only focused on the “what” and “where;” no questions asked.”</summary></entry></feed>