<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-01-08T00:38:48-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Evolve or Die</title><subtitle>Mainly about technology, management, ideas</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The evolution of cooperation - 9</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/personal_development/reading_notes/2022/01/07/the-evolution-of-cooperation-9.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The evolution of cooperation - 9" /><published>2022-01-07T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-01-07T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/personal_development/reading_notes/2022/01/07/the-evolution-of-cooperation-9</id><author><name></name></author><category term="personal_development" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“There is yet a third way in which some of the tournament rules are too clever: they employ a probabilistic strategy that is so complex that it cannot be distinguished by the other strategies from a purely random choice. In other words, too much complexity can appear to be total chaos. If you are using a strategy which appears random, then you also appear unresponsive to the other player. If you are unresponsive, then the other player has no incentive to cooperate with you. So being so complex as to be incomprehensible is very dangerous.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The evolution of cooperation - 8</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/personal_development/reading_notes/2022/01/07/the-evolution-of-cooperation-8.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The evolution of cooperation - 8" /><published>2022-01-07T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-01-07T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/personal_development/reading_notes/2022/01/07/the-evolution-of-cooperation-8</id><author><name></name></author><category term="personal_development" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“When the future of the interaction is not important enough relative to immediate gains from defection, then simply waiting for the other to defect is not such a good idea. It is important to bear in mind that TIT FOR TAT is a stable strategy only when the discount parameter, w, is high enough relative to the payoff parameters, R, S, T, and P. In particular, proposition 2 shows that if the discount parameter is not high enough and the other player is using TIT FOR TAT, a player is better off alternating defection and cooperation, or even always defecting. Therefore, if the other player is not likely to be seen again, defecting right away is better than being nice.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The evolution of cooperation - 7</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/personal_development/reading_notes/2022/01/07/the-evolution-of-cooperation-7.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The evolution of cooperation - 7" /><published>2022-01-07T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-01-07T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/personal_development/reading_notes/2022/01/07/the-evolution-of-cooperation-7</id><author><name></name></author><category term="personal_development" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“The chronological story that emerges from this analysis is the following. ALL D is the primeval state and is evolu-tionarily stable. But cooperation based on reciprocity can gain a foothold through two different mechanisms. First, there can be kinship between mutant strategies, giving the genes of the mutants some stake in each other’s success, thereby altering the payoff of the interaction when viewed from the perspective of the gene rather than the individual. A second mechanism to overcome total defection is for the mutant strategies to arrive in a cluster so that they provide a nontrivial proportion of the interactions each has, even if they are so few as to provide a negligible proportion of the interactions which the ALL D individuals have. Then the tournament approach described in chapter 2 demonstrates that once a variety of strategies is present, TIT FOR TAT is an extremely robust one. It does well in a wide range of circumstances and gradually displaces all other strategies in an ecological simulation that contains a great variety of more or less sophisticated decision rules. And if the probability that interaction between two individuals will continue is great enough, then TIT FOR TAT is an extremely robust one. It does well in a wide range of circumstances and gradually displaces all other strategies in an ecological simulation that contains a great variety of more or less sophisticated decision rules. And if the probability that interaction between two individuals will continue is great enough, then TIT FOR TAT is itself evolution-arily stable. Moreover, its stability is especially secure because it can resist the intrusion of whole clusters of mutant strategies. Thus cooperation based on reciprocity can get started in a predominantly noncooperative world, can thrive in a variegated environment, and can defend itself once fully established.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The evolution of cooperation - 6</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/personal_development/reading_notes/2021/12/29/the-evolution-of-cooperation-6.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The evolution of cooperation - 6" /><published>2021-12-29T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-12-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/personal_development/reading_notes/2021/12/29/the-evolution-of-cooperation-6</id><author><name></name></author><category term="personal_development" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“Proposition 4. For a nice strategy to be collectively stable, it must be provoked by the very first defection of the other player. The reason is simple enough. If a nice strategy were not provoked by a defection on move n, then it would not be collectively stable because it could be invaded by a rule which defected only on move n.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The evolution of cooperation - 5</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/personal_development/reading_notes/2021/12/29/the-evolution-of-cooperation-5.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The evolution of cooperation - 5" /><published>2021-12-29T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-12-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/personal_development/reading_notes/2021/12/29/the-evolution-of-cooperation-5</id><author><name></name></author><category term="personal_development" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“What accounts for TIT FOR TAT’s robust success is its combination of being nice, retaliatory, forgiving, and clear. Its niceness prevents it from getting into unnecessary trouble. Its retaliation discourages the other side from persisting whenever defection is tried. Its forgiveness helps restore mutual cooperation. And its clarity makes it intelligible to the other player, thereby eliciting long-term cooperation.”</summary></entry></feed>