<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-11-28T11:32:41-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Evolve or Die</title><subtitle>Mainly about technology, management, ideas</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Big Debt Crisis - 5</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/reading_notes/2021/11/27/big-debt-crisis-5.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Big Debt Crisis - 5" /><published>2021-11-27T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-11-27T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/reading_notes/2021/11/27/big-debt-crisis-5</id><author><name></name></author><category term="investment" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">Typically, in the early stages of the top, the rise in short rates narrows or eliminates the spread with long rates (i.e., the extra interest rate earned for lending long term rather than short term), lessening the incentive to lend relative to the incentive to hold cash. As a result of the yield curve being flat or inverted (i.e., long-term interest rates are at their lowest relative to short-term interest rates), people are incentivized to move to cash just before the bubble pops, slowing credit growth and causing the previously described dynamic. Unemployment is normally at cyclical lows and inflation rates are rising. The increase in short-term interest rates makes holding cash more attractive, and it raises the interest rate used to discount the future cash flows of assets, weakening riskier asset prices and slowing lending. It also makes items bought on credit de facto more expensive, slowing demand. Short rates typically peak just a few months before the top in the stock market.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Big Debt Crisis - 4</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/reading_notes/2021/11/25/big-debt-crisis-4.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Big Debt Crisis - 4" /><published>2021-11-25T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-11-25T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/reading_notes/2021/11/25/big-debt-crisis-4</id><author><name></name></author><category term="investment" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">In many cases, monetary policy helps inflate the bubble rather than constrain it. This is especially true when inflation and growth are both good and investment returns are great. Such periods are typically interpreted to be a productivity boom that reinforces investor optimism as they leverage up to buy investment assets. In such cases, central banks, focusing on inflation and growth, are often reluctant to adequately tighten money. This is what happened in Japan in the late 1980s, and in much of the world in the late 1920s and mid-2000s. This is one of the biggest problems with most central bank policies—i.e., because central bankers target either inflation or inflation and growth and don’t target the management of bubbles, the debt growth that they enable can go to finance the creation of bubbles if inflation and real growth don’t appear to be too strong. In my opinion it’s very important for central banks to target debt growth with an eye toward keeping it at a sustainable level — i.e., at a level where the growth in income is likely to be large enough to service the debts regardless of what credit is used to buy. Central bankers sometimes say that it is too hard to spot bubbles and that it’s not their role to assess and control them—that it is their job to control inflation and growth. But what they control is money and credit, and when that money and credit goes into debts that can’t be paid back, that has huge implications for growth and inflation down the road. The greatest depressions occur when bubbles burst, and if the central banks that are producing the debts that are inflating them won’t control them, then who will? The economic pain of allowing a large bubble to inflate and then burst is so high that it is imprudent for policy makers to ignore them, and I hope their perspective will change.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Big Debt Crisis - 3</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/reading_notes/2021/11/25/big-debt-crisis-3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Big Debt Crisis - 3" /><published>2021-11-25T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-11-25T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/reading_notes/2021/11/25/big-debt-crisis-3</id><author><name></name></author><category term="investment" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">While the central bank can alleviate typical debt crises by lowering real and nominal interest rates, severe debt crises (i.e., depressions) occur when this is no longer possible. Classically, a lot of short-term debt cycles (i.e., business cycles) add up to a long-term debt cycle, because each short-term cyclical high and each short-term cyclical low is higher in its debt-to-income ratio than the one before it, until the interest rate reductions that helped fuel the expansion in debt can no longer continue. In the short-term debt cycle, spending is constrained only by the willingness of lenders and borrowers to provide and receive credit. When credit is easily available, there’s an economic expansion. When credit isn’t easily avail able, there’s a recession. The availability of credit is controlled primarily by the central bank. The central bank is generally able to bring the economy out of a recession by easing rates to stimulate the cycle anew. But over time, each bottom and top of the cycle finishes with more economic activity than the previous cycle, and with more debt. Why? Because people push it—they have an inclination to borrow and spend more instead of paying back debt. It’s human nature. As a result, over long periods of time, debts rise faster than incomes. This creates the long-term debt cycle</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Big Debt Crisis - 2</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/reading_notes/2021/11/25/big-debt-crisis-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Big Debt Crisis - 2" /><published>2021-11-25T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-11-25T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/reading_notes/2021/11/25/big-debt-crisis-2</id><author><name></name></author><category term="investment" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">Most of the really terrible economic problems that debt crises have caused occurred before policy makers took steps to spread them out. Even the biggest debt crises in history (e.g., the 1930s Great Depression) were gotten past once the right adjustments were made. From my examination of these cases, the biggest risks are not from the debts themselves but from a) the failure of policy makers to do the right things, due to a lack of knowledge and/or lack of authority, and b) the political consequences of making adjustments that hurt some people in the process of helping others. It is from a desire to help reduce these risks that I have written this study.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Big Debt Crisis - 1</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/reading_notes/2021/11/25/big-debt-crisis-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Big Debt Crisis - 1" /><published>2021-11-25T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-11-25T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/reading_notes/2021/11/25/big-debt-crisis-1</id><author><name></name></author><category term="investment" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">Credit is the giving of buying power. This buying power is granted in exchange for a promise to pay it back, which is debt. Clearly, giving the ability to make purchases by providing credit is, in and of itself, a good thing, and not providing the power to buy and do good things can be a bad thing. For example, if there is very little credit provided for development, then there is very little development, which is a bad thing. The problem with debt arises when there is an inability to pay it back. Said differently, the question of whether rapid credit/debt growth is a good or bad thing hinges on what that credit produces and how the debt is repaid (i.e., how the debt is serviced)</summary></entry></feed>