<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-05-30T12:10:12-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Evolve or Die</title><subtitle>Mainly about technology, management, ideas</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Radical Candor - 7</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/30/radical-candor-7.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Radical Candor - 7" /><published>2022-05-30T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-05-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/30/radical-candor-7</id><author><name></name></author><category term="management" /><category term="leadership" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“This is an extreme example of what I call Ruinous Empathy. Ruinous Empathy is responsible for the vast majority of management mistakes I’ve seen in my career. Most people want to avoid creating tension or discomfort at work. They are like the well-meaning parent who cannot bear to discipline their kids. ”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Radical Candor - 6</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/30/radical-candor-6.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Radical Candor - 6" /><published>2022-05-30T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-05-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/30/radical-candor-6</id><author><name></name></author><category term="management" /><category term="leadership" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“A couple of months after joining Google, I had a disagreement with Larry Page about his approach to a policy. In a fit of frustration, I sent an email to about thirty people, including Larry, which said, “Larry claims he wants to organize the world’s information, but his policy is creating ‘clutter sites,’ muddling the world’s information.” I went on to imply that he was recommending the policy because he was focused on increasing Google’s revenue rather than doing the right thing for users.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Radical Candor - 5</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/30/radical-candor-5.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Radical Candor - 5" /><published>2022-05-30T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-05-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/30/radical-candor-5</id><author><name></name></author><category term="management" /><category term="leadership" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“THINK FOR A moment about how Sheryl handled that situation. Even though the overall talk had gone well, she didn’t let the positive result get in the way of pointing out something I needed to fix. She did so immediately, so that the problem didn’t hurt my reputation at Google. She made sure to point out the positive things I’d accomplished in the presentation, and what’s more, she did so thoroughly and sincerely—there was no attempt at “sandwiching” the criticism between bogus positives. Her first approach was gentle but direct. When it became clear that I wasn’t hearing her, she became more direct, but even then she was careful not to “personalize,” not to make it about some essential trait. She said I “sounded” stupid rather than I was stupid. And I wasn’t in this alone: she offered tangible help. I didn’t feel like an idiot with defects, but a valuable team member she was ready to invest in. But it still stung a little bit.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Radical Candor - 4</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/22/radical-candor-4.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Radical Candor - 4" /><published>2022-05-22T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-05-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/22/radical-candor-4</id><author><name></name></author><category term="management" /><category term="leadership" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“Challenging others and encouraging them to challenge you helps build trusting relationships because it shows 1) you care enough to point out both the things that aren’t going well and those that are and that 2) you are willing to admit when you’re wrong and that you are committed to fixing mistakes that you or others have made. But because challenging often involves disagreeing or saying no, this approach embraces conflict rather than avoiding it. Former Secretary of State Colin Powell once remarked that being responsible sometimes means pissing people off. 4 You have to accept that sometimes people on your team will be mad at you. In fact, if nobody is ever mad at you, you probably aren’t challenging your team enough. The key, as in any relationship, is how you handle the anger. When what you say hurts, acknowledge the other person’s pain. Don’t pretend it doesn’t hurt or say it “shouldn’t” hurt—just show that you care. Eliminate the phrase “don’t take it personally” from your vocabulary—it’s insulting. Instead, offer to help fix the problem.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Radical Candor - 3</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/22/radical-candor-3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Radical Candor - 3" /><published>2022-05-22T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-05-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/22/radical-candor-3</id><author><name></name></author><category term="management" /><category term="leadership" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“The first dimension is about being more than “just professional.” It’s about giving a damn, sharing more than just your work self, and encouraging everyone who reports to you to do the same. It’s not enough to care only about people’s ability to perform a job. To have a good relationship, you have to be your whole self and care about each of the people who work for you as a human being. It’s not just business; it is personal, and deeply personal. I call this dimension “Care Personally.”</summary></entry></feed>