<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-05-09T00:29:21-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Evolve or Die</title><subtitle>Mainly about technology, management, ideas</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The manager’s path - 14</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/08/the-manager-path-14.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The manager’s path - 14" /><published>2022-05-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-05-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/08/the-manager-path-14</id><author><name></name></author><category term="management" /><category term="leadership" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“The negative person is easier to deal with than the brilliant jerk. Make it clear to him that the behavior has to change, bring clear examples, and provide corrective feedback quickly after things happen. Sometimes the negative person is just unhappy and the best thing to do is to help him leave the team on good terms; you must be prepared for this outcome. Other times, the person has no idea about the impact he’s having on the team, and a quick chat will be all that’s needed to curtail the incidents. Be careful that vocally negative people don’t stay in that mindset on your team for long. The kind of toxic drama that is created by these energy vampires is hard for even the best manager to combat. The best defense is a good offense in this case, and quick action is essential.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The manager’s path - 13</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/04/the-manager-path-13.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The manager’s path - 13" /><published>2022-05-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-05-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/04/the-manager-path-13</id><author><name></name></author><category term="management" /><category term="leadership" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“I have an employee who seems stuck. He’s been with the company for a couple of years and done OK work, but I don’t think he has the potential to be promoted further on our team. Every time he asks what he needs to do to get to the next level, I tell him, but he then goes back to his comfort zone, and no amount of nudging seems to bring about any change. What should I do? This is a fairly common occurrence that managers have to handle. You have an employee who has topped out in the organization and seems to be losing energy. He has achieved expectations in his level, but can’t figure out how to grow enough to get to the next level, despite your efforts. It may be time to coach him out. Many organizations have a rule of “up or out” for early-career employees. The entry levels of most engineering career ladders expect that people at those levels will progress within a certain period of time, and if they don’t, they aren’t meeting expectations and will be fired. Generally, you want to make sure that long-term employees are capable of doing their day-to-day work independently, without a lot of oversight or help. However, once people have gotten past these up-or-out career points, what do you do when they get stuck? Some people will be happy cruising as senior engineers or managers at a certain level for their whole careers, and if you’re both satisfied with the work, there’s nothing wrong with that. Others, like your employee, want to progress but for whatever reason don’t seem to be able to do it on your team. You owe it to your employee to be clear that this is the case. This is what is meant by “coaching out.” Make the situation clear to him. You have told him repeatedly what the next level looks like, and he has not been able to show that he can work at that level, so you don’t think that your team is the right place for him to grow his career. You aren’t firing him, but you are telling him that he needs to move on if he wants to progress. Give the employee a chance to find a job in another part of the organization or at another company. When he does, let him go happily, and do your best to retain goodwill. Former couples who break up because they don’t see a future together can remain friends, and the same goes for former employees who simply need a different team or company to shine.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The manager’s path - 12</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/04/the-manager-path-12.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The manager’s path - 12" /><published>2022-05-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-05-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/04/the-manager-path-12</id><author><name></name></author><category term="management" /><category term="leadership" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“You want to celebrate achievements, talk about what’s going well, and give plenty of praise for good work. This goes not only for the writing process but also—and especially—for the delivery. Don’t let people skip over the good stuff in order to obsess over the areas for improvement, as many will want to do. Those strengths are what you’ll use to determine when people should be promoted, and it is important to write them down and reflect on them.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The manager’s path - 11</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/01/the-manager-path-11.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The manager’s path - 11" /><published>2022-05-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-05-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/01/the-manager-path-11</id><author><name></name></author><category term="management" /><category term="leadership" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“Sometimes it helps to have a goal, so task yourself with regularly identifying people who deserve praise. Adopting a habit of positive recognition forces you to be on the lookout for things to praise, which in turn causes you to pay attention to what individuals are bringing to various projects. You don’t have to do this in public, but every week there should be at least one thing you can recognize about someone on your team. Even better, look for something to recognize weekly for everyone who reports to you.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">读书日谈读书 有感</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/reading_notes/2022/04/23/%E8%AF%BB%E4%B9%A6%E6%97%A5%E8%B0%88%E8%AF%BB%E4%B9%A6%E6%9C%89%E6%84%9F.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="读书日谈读书 有感" /><published>2022-04-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-04-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/reading_notes/2022/04/23/%E8%AF%BB%E4%B9%A6%E6%97%A5%E8%B0%88%E8%AF%BB%E4%B9%A6%E6%9C%89%E6%84%9F</id><author><name></name></author><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">《读书日谈读书》是翟东升老师在b站上写的一篇文章，里面谈了他是如何选书、读书以及突破书本身的牢笼的。读下来感觉有不少观点是和我自己的感受有类似的地方的。</summary></entry></feed>