<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-05-22T21:28:44-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Evolve or Die</title><subtitle>Mainly about technology, management, ideas</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Radical Candor - 3</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/22/radical-candor-3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Radical Candor - 3" /><published>2022-05-22T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-05-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/22/radical-candor-3</id><author><name></name></author><category term="management" /><category term="leadership" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“The first dimension is about being more than “just professional.” It’s about giving a damn, sharing more than just your work self, and encouraging everyone who reports to you to do the same. It’s not enough to care only about people’s ability to perform a job. To have a good relationship, you have to be your whole self and care about each of the people who work for you as a human being. It’s not just business; it is personal, and deeply personal. I call this dimension “Care Personally.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Radical Candor - 2</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/22/radical-candor-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Radical Candor - 2" /><published>2022-05-22T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-05-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/22/radical-candor-2</id><author><name></name></author><category term="management" /><category term="leadership" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“Nevertheless, these relationships are core to your job. They determine whether you can fulfill your three responsibilities as a manager: 1) to create a culture of guidance (praise and criticism) that will keep everyone moving in the right direction; 2) to understand what motivates each person on your team well enough to avoid burnout or boredom and keep the team cohesive; and 3) to drive results collaboratively. If you think that you can do these things without strong relationships, you are kidding yourself.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The manager’s path - 17</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/15/the-manager-path-17.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The manager’s path - 17" /><published>2022-05-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-05-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/15/the-manager-path-17</id><author><name></name></author><category term="management" /><category term="leadership" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“I have some quibbles with that. Employees with obligations that take them out of the office at a strict time every day are no more or less engaged than those who are willing to stand around and chat. The larger point, however, is still a good one. Most gelled teams have a sense of camaraderie that makes them joke together, get coffee, share lunch, and feel friendly toward one another. They may have obligations they respect, and passions outside of work, but they don’t view their team as something they’re eager to escape every day. The real goal here is psychological safety—that is, a team whose members are willing to take risks and make mistakes in front of one another. This is the underpinning of a successful team. The work of gelling a team begins by creating the friendliness that leads to psychological safety. You can encourage this by taking the time to get to know people as human beings and asking them about their extracurricular lives and interests. Let them share what they feel comfortable sharing. Ask how their child’s birthday party went, how their ski trip was, how their marathon training is going. This is more than empty small talk; it fosters relatedness, the sense of people as individuals and not just anonymous cogs.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The manager’s path - 16</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/15/the-manager-path-16.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The manager’s path - 16" /><published>2022-05-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-05-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/15/the-manager-path-16</id><author><name></name></author><category term="management" /><category term="leadership" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“Don’t rely exclusively on consensus or voting. Consensus can appear morally authoritative, but that assumes that everyone involved in the voting process is impartial, has an equal stake in the various outcomes, and has equal knowledge of the context. These conditions are rarely met on teams where each person has different levels of expertise and different roles”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Radical Candor - 1</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/15/radical-candor-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Radical Candor - 1" /><published>2022-05-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-05-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/15/radical-candor-1</id><author><name></name></author><category term="management" /><category term="leadership" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“Then a leader at Apple pointed out to me that all teams need stability as well as growth to function properly; nothing works well if everyone is gunning for the next promotion. She called the people on her team who got exceptional results but who were on a more gradual growth trajectory “rock stars” because they were like the Rock of Gibraltar on her team. These people loved their work and were world-class at it, but they didn’t want her job or to be Steve Jobs. They were happy where they were. The people who were on a steeper growth trajectory—the ones who’d go crazy if they were still doing the same job in a year—she called “superstars.” They were the source of growth on any team. She was explicit about needing a balance of both”</summary></entry></feed>