<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-01-29T00:01:52-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Evolve or Die</title><subtitle>Mainly about technology, management, ideas</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Wherever you go there you are - 10</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/personal_development/reading_notes/2022/01/23/wherever-you-go-there-you-are-10.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wherever you go there you are - 10" /><published>2022-01-23T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-01-23T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/personal_development/reading_notes/2022/01/23/wherever-you-go-there-you-are-10</id><author><name></name></author><category term="personal_development" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“Siddhartha listened. He was now listening intently, completely absorbed, quite empty, taking in everything. He felt that he had now completely learned the art of listening. He had often heard all this before, all these numerous voices in the river, but today they sounded different. He could no longer distinguish the different voices—the merry voice from the weeping voice, the childish voice from the manly voice. They all belonged to each other: the lament of those who yearn, the laughter of the wise, the cry of indignation and the groan of the dying. They were all interwoven and interlocked, entwined in a thousand ways. And all the voices, all the goals, all the pleasures, all the good and evil, all of them together was the world. All of them together was the stream of events, the music of life. When Siddhartha listened attentively to this river, to this song of a thousand voices, when he did not listen to the sorrow or the laughter, when he did not bind his soul to any one particular voice and absorb it in his Self, but heard them all, the whole, the unity, then the great song of a thousand voices consisted of one word.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Wherever you go three you are - 5</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/personal_development/reading_notes/2022/01/17/wherever-you-go-there-you-are-5.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wherever you go three you are - 5" /><published>2022-01-17T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-01-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/personal_development/reading_notes/2022/01/17/wherever-you-go-there-you-are-5</id><author><name></name></author><category term="personal_development" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“Awareness is not the same as thought. It lies beyond thinking, although it makes use of thinking, honoring its value and its power. Awareness is more like a vessel which can hold and contain our thinking, helping us to see and know our thoughts as thoughts rather than getting caught up in them as reality.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Wherever you go three you are - 4</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/personal_development/reading_notes/2022/01/17/wherever-you-go-there-you-are-4.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wherever you go three you are - 4" /><published>2022-01-17T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-01-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/personal_development/reading_notes/2022/01/17/wherever-you-go-there-you-are-4</id><author><name></name></author><category term="personal_development" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“If you hope to bring meditation into your life in any kind of long-term, committed way, you will need a vision that is truly your own—one that is deep and tenacious and that lies close to the core of who you believe yourself to be, what you value in your life, and where you see yourself going. Only the strength of such a dynamic vision and the motivation from which it springs can possibly keep you on this path year in and year out, with a willingness to practice every day and to bring mindfulness to bear on whatever is happening, to open to whatever is perceived, and to let it point to where the holding is and where the letting go and the growing need to happen.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Wherever you go three you are - 3</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/personal_development/reading_notes/2022/01/17/wherever-you-go-there-you-are-3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wherever you go three you are - 3" /><published>2022-01-17T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-01-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/personal_development/reading_notes/2022/01/17/wherever-you-go-there-you-are-3</id><author><name></name></author><category term="personal_development" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“See if you can be in touch with a core within you which is rich beyond reckoning in all important ways. Let that core start radiating its energy outwardly, through your entire body, and beyond. Experiment with giving away this energy—in little ways at first—directing it toward yourself and toward others with no thought of gain or return. Give more than you think you can, trusting that you are richer than you think. Celebrate this richness. Give as if you had inexhaustible wealth. This is called “kingly giving.” I am not talking solely of money or material possessions, although it can be wonderfully growth-enhancing, uplifting, and truly helpful to share material abundance. Rather, what is being suggested here is that you practice sharing the fullness of your being, your best self, your enthusiasm, your vitality, your spirit, your trust, your openness, above all, your presence. Share it with yourself, with your family, with the world.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Wherever you go three you are - 2</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/personal_development/reading_notes/2022/01/15/wherever-you-go-there-you-are-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wherever you go three you are - 2" /><published>2022-01-15T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-01-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/personal_development/reading_notes/2022/01/15/wherever-you-go-there-you-are-2</id><author><name></name></author><category term="personal_development" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“Effortless activity happens at moments in dance and in sports at the highest levels of performance; when it does, it takes everybody’s breath away. But it also happens in every area of human activity, from painting to car repair to parenting. Years of practice and experience combine on some occasions, giving rise to a new capacity to let execution unfold beyond technique, beyond exertion, beyond thinking. Action then becomes a pure expression of art, of being, of letting go of all doing—a merging of mind and body in motion. We thrill in watching a superb performance, whether athletic or artistic, because it allows us to participate in the magic of true mastery, to be uplifted, if only briefly, and perhaps to share in the intention that each of us, in our own way, might touch such moments of grace and harmony in the living of our own lives.”</summary></entry></feed>