<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-04-23T18:55:28-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Evolve or Die</title><subtitle>Mainly about technology, management, ideas</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The manager’s path - 7</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/04/23/the-manager-path-7.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The manager’s path - 7" /><published>2022-04-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-04-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/04/23/the-manager-path-7</id><author><name></name></author><category term="management" /><category term="leadership" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“As the manager of a process czar, help that person get more comfortable with ambiguity. As with many of the manager pitfalls, an obsession with process can be related to a fear of failure and a desire to control things to prevent the unexpected. If you are honest and make it clear that it’s safe to fail and to be imperfect, that’s often enough to get your process czar to relax a little bit and let some ambiguity in. It is very important to keep process czars from spending all of their time seeking out the perfect tool or process, and especially important to make sure that they aren’t punishing their teams for failing to follow processes.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The manager’s path - 6</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/04/09/the-manager-path-6.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The manager’s path - 6" /><published>2022-04-09T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-04-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/04/09/the-manager-path-6</id><author><name></name></author><category term="management" /><category term="leadership" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“Run the project and adjust the plan as you go. The value of a good planning process is that it helps you know approximately how far the project has come, and approximately how far it is from completion. As things slip (and they always do), keep everyone apprised of the status. But now, instead of guessing how far you have to go, you can clearly point to the milestones that have been hit and outline the expected remaining work.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The manager’s path - 5</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/04/08/the-manager-path-5.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The manager’s path - 5" /><published>2022-04-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-04-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/04/08/the-manager-path-5</id><author><name></name></author><category term="management" /><category term="leadership" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“Ultimately, the value of planning isn’t that you execute the plan perfectly, that you catch every detail beforehand, or that you predict the future; it’s that you enforce the self-discipline to think about the project in some depth before diving in and seeing what happens. A degree of forethought, in places where you can reasonably make predictions and plans, is the goal. The plan itself, however accurate it turns out, is less important than spending time on the act of planning.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The manager’s path - 4</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/04/08/the-manager-path-4.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The manager’s path - 4" /><published>2022-04-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-04-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/04/08/the-manager-path-4</id><author><name></name></author><category term="management" /><category term="leadership" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“It can be hard to balance the work of project management and oversight with hands-on technical delivery. Some days you’re on a maker’s schedule, and some days you’re on a manager’s schedule. Through trial and error, you’ll need to learn how to manage your time to provide yourself with appropriately sized blocks to work in. The worst scheduling mistake is allowing yourself to get pulled randomly into meetings. It is very difficult to get into the groove of writing code if you’re interrupted every hour by a meeting.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The manager’s path - 3</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/04/03/the-manager-path-3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The manager’s path - 3" /><published>2022-04-03T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-04-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/04/03/the-manager-path-3</id><author><name></name></author><category term="management" /><category term="leadership" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“The tech lead role is not a point on the ladder, but a set of responsibilities that any engineer may take on once they reach the senior level. This role may or may not include people management, but if it does, the tech lead is expected to manage these team members to the high management standards of RTR tech. These standards include: Regular (weekly) 1-1 touchbases Regular feedback on career growth, progression towards goals, areas for improvement, and praise as warranted Working with reports to identify areas for learning and helping them grow in these areas via project work, external learning, or additional mentoring If a tech lead is not managing directly, they are still expected to provide mentorship and guidance to the other members of the team. The tech lead is learning how to be a strong technical project manager, and as such, they are scaling themselves by delegating work effectively without micromanaging. They focus on the whole team’s productivity and strive to increase the impact of the team’s work product. They are empowered to make independent decisions for the team and are learning how to handle difficult management and leadership situations. They are also learning how to partner effectively with product, analytics, and other areas of the business. It is not required that an engineer work as a tech lead to progress, but it is the most common way for engineers to grow from senior engineer 1 -&amp;gt; 2 and is required to grow from senior engineer 2 to engineering lead. Realistically it is very hard to grow past senior engineer 2 without ever having acted as a tech lead, even on the individual contributor track, due to the importance at senior levels of leadership and responsibility.”</summary></entry></feed>