<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-05-30T11:51:58-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Evolve or Die</title><subtitle>Mainly about technology, management, ideas</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Radical Candor - 5</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/30/radical-candor-5.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Radical Candor - 5" /><published>2022-05-30T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-05-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/30/radical-candor-5</id><author><name></name></author><category term="management" /><category term="leadership" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“THINK FOR A moment about how Sheryl handled that situation. Even though the overall talk had gone well, she didn’t let the positive result get in the way of pointing out something I needed to fix. She did so immediately, so that the problem didn’t hurt my reputation at Google. She made sure to point out the positive things I’d accomplished in the presentation, and what’s more, she did so thoroughly and sincerely—there was no attempt at “sandwiching” the criticism between bogus positives. Her first approach was gentle but direct. When it became clear that I wasn’t hearing her, she became more direct, but even then she was careful not to “personalize,” not to make it about some essential trait. She said I “sounded” stupid rather than I was stupid. And I wasn’t in this alone: she offered tangible help. I didn’t feel like an idiot with defects, but a valuable team member she was ready to invest in. But it still stung a little bit.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Radical Candor - 4</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/22/radical-candor-4.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Radical Candor - 4" /><published>2022-05-22T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-05-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/22/radical-candor-4</id><author><name></name></author><category term="management" /><category term="leadership" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“Challenging others and encouraging them to challenge you helps build trusting relationships because it shows 1) you care enough to point out both the things that aren’t going well and those that are and that 2) you are willing to admit when you’re wrong and that you are committed to fixing mistakes that you or others have made. But because challenging often involves disagreeing or saying no, this approach embraces conflict rather than avoiding it. Former Secretary of State Colin Powell once remarked that being responsible sometimes means pissing people off. 4 You have to accept that sometimes people on your team will be mad at you. In fact, if nobody is ever mad at you, you probably aren’t challenging your team enough. The key, as in any relationship, is how you handle the anger. When what you say hurts, acknowledge the other person’s pain. Don’t pretend it doesn’t hurt or say it “shouldn’t” hurt—just show that you care. Eliminate the phrase “don’t take it personally” from your vocabulary—it’s insulting. Instead, offer to help fix the problem.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Radical Candor - 3</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/22/radical-candor-3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Radical Candor - 3" /><published>2022-05-22T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-05-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/22/radical-candor-3</id><author><name></name></author><category term="management" /><category term="leadership" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“The first dimension is about being more than “just professional.” It’s about giving a damn, sharing more than just your work self, and encouraging everyone who reports to you to do the same. It’s not enough to care only about people’s ability to perform a job. To have a good relationship, you have to be your whole self and care about each of the people who work for you as a human being. It’s not just business; it is personal, and deeply personal. I call this dimension “Care Personally.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Radical Candor - 2</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/22/radical-candor-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Radical Candor - 2" /><published>2022-05-22T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-05-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/22/radical-candor-2</id><author><name></name></author><category term="management" /><category term="leadership" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“Nevertheless, these relationships are core to your job. They determine whether you can fulfill your three responsibilities as a manager: 1) to create a culture of guidance (praise and criticism) that will keep everyone moving in the right direction; 2) to understand what motivates each person on your team well enough to avoid burnout or boredom and keep the team cohesive; and 3) to drive results collaboratively. If you think that you can do these things without strong relationships, you are kidding yourself.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The manager’s path - 17</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/15/the-manager-path-17.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The manager’s path - 17" /><published>2022-05-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-05-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/15/the-manager-path-17</id><author><name></name></author><category term="management" /><category term="leadership" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“I have some quibbles with that. Employees with obligations that take them out of the office at a strict time every day are no more or less engaged than those who are willing to stand around and chat. The larger point, however, is still a good one. Most gelled teams have a sense of camaraderie that makes them joke together, get coffee, share lunch, and feel friendly toward one another. They may have obligations they respect, and passions outside of work, but they don’t view their team as something they’re eager to escape every day. The real goal here is psychological safety—that is, a team whose members are willing to take risks and make mistakes in front of one another. This is the underpinning of a successful team. The work of gelling a team begins by creating the friendliness that leads to psychological safety. You can encourage this by taking the time to get to know people as human beings and asking them about their extracurricular lives and interests. Let them share what they feel comfortable sharing. Ask how their child’s birthday party went, how their ski trip was, how their marathon training is going. This is more than empty small talk; it fosters relatedness, the sense of people as individuals and not just anonymous cogs.”</summary></entry></feed>