<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-12-24T23:50:06-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Evolve or Die</title><subtitle>Mainly about technology, management, ideas</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The evolution of cooperation - 1</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/personal_development/reading_notes/2021/12/24/the-evolution-of-cooperation-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The evolution of cooperation - 1" /><published>2021-12-24T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-12-24T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/personal_development/reading_notes/2021/12/24/the-evolution-of-cooperation-1</id><author><name></name></author><category term="personal_development" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“We all know that people are not angels, and that they tend to look after themselves and their own first. Yet we also know that cooperation does occur and that our civilization is based upon it. But, in situations where each individual has an incentive to be selfish, how can cooperation ever develop?” “The approach of this book is to investigate how individuals pursuing their own interests will act, followed by an analysis of what effects this will have for the system as a whole. Put another way, the approach is to make some assumptions about individual motives and then deduce consequences for the behavior of the entire system (Schelling 1978). The case of the U.S. Senate is a good example, but the same style of reasoning can be applied to other settings.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Big Debt Crisis - 12</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/reading_notes/2021/12/12/big-debt-crisis-12.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Big Debt Crisis - 12" /><published>2021-12-12T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-12-12T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/reading_notes/2021/12/12/big-debt-crisis-12</id><author><name></name></author><category term="investment" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">Asset/currency holders typically worry that policy makers will impose restrictions on their ability to get their money out of the country, which encourages them to get their money out while they still can, which further increases the balance of payments problem. Policy makers worry about capital outflows and the possibility of a currency collapse. As the balance of payments deteriorate, the central bank’s job becomes more difficult—i.e., it gets less economic growth per unit of inflation because the negative flows lead the currency to depreciate, interest rates to rise, and/or reserves to decline, depending on how the central bank chooses to handle it.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Big Debt Crisis - 11</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/reading_notes/2021/12/12/big-debt-crisis-11.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Big Debt Crisis - 11" /><published>2021-12-12T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-12-12T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/reading_notes/2021/12/12/big-debt-crisis-11</id><author><name></name></author><category term="investment" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">As the bubble emerges, there are fewer productive investments, and at the same time there is more capital going after them. The fundamental attractiveness of the country that sparked the boom fades, in part because the rising currency is eroding the country’s competitiveness.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Big Debt Crisis - 10</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/reading_notes/2021/12/12/big-debt-crisis-10.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Big Debt Crisis - 10" /><published>2021-12-12T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-12-12T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/reading_notes/2021/12/12/big-debt-crisis-10</id><author><name></name></author><category term="investment" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">The bubble emerges in the midst of a self-reinforcing virtuous cycle of strong capital flows, good asset returns, and strong economic conditions. The capital that came in during the early upswing produced good returns, as it was invested productively and led to asset price appreciation, which attracted even more capital. In the bubble phase, the prices of the currency and/or the assets get bid up and increasingly financed by debt, making the prices of these investments too high to produce adequate returns, but the borrowing and buying continues because prices are rising, and so debts rise rapidly relative to incomes.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Big Debt Crisis - 9</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/reading_notes/2021/12/08/big-debt-crisis-9.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Big Debt Crisis - 9" /><published>2021-12-08T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-12-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/reading_notes/2021/12/08/big-debt-crisis-9</id><author><name></name></author><category term="investment" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">If a currency falls in relation to another currency at a rate that is greater than the currency’s interest rate, the holder of the debt in the weakening currency will lose money. If investors expect that weakness to continue without being compensated with higher interest rates, a dangerous currency dynamic will develop.</summary></entry></feed>