<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-12-13T00:12:35-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Evolve or Die</title><subtitle>Mainly about technology, management, ideas</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Big Debt Crisis - 12</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/reading_notes/2021/12/12/big-debt-crisis-12.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Big Debt Crisis - 12" /><published>2021-12-12T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-12-12T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/reading_notes/2021/12/12/big-debt-crisis-12</id><author><name></name></author><category term="investment" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">Asset/currency holders typically worry that policy makers will impose restrictions on their ability to get their money out of the country, which encourages them to get their money out while they still can, which further increases the balance of payments problem. Policy makers worry about capital outflows and the possibility of a currency collapse. As the balance of payments deteriorate, the central bank’s job becomes more difficult—i.e., it gets less economic growth per unit of inflation because the negative flows lead the currency to depreciate, interest rates to rise, and/or reserves to decline, depending on how the central bank chooses to handle it.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Big Debt Crisis - 11</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/reading_notes/2021/12/12/big-debt-crisis-11.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Big Debt Crisis - 11" /><published>2021-12-12T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-12-12T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/reading_notes/2021/12/12/big-debt-crisis-11</id><author><name></name></author><category term="investment" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">As the bubble emerges, there are fewer productive investments, and at the same time there is more capital going after them. The fundamental attractiveness of the country that sparked the boom fades, in part because the rising currency is eroding the country’s competitiveness.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Big Debt Crisis - 10</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/reading_notes/2021/12/12/big-debt-crisis-10.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Big Debt Crisis - 10" /><published>2021-12-12T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-12-12T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/reading_notes/2021/12/12/big-debt-crisis-10</id><author><name></name></author><category term="investment" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">The bubble emerges in the midst of a self-reinforcing virtuous cycle of strong capital flows, good asset returns, and strong economic conditions. The capital that came in during the early upswing produced good returns, as it was invested productively and led to asset price appreciation, which attracted even more capital. In the bubble phase, the prices of the currency and/or the assets get bid up and increasingly financed by debt, making the prices of these investments too high to produce adequate returns, but the borrowing and buying continues because prices are rising, and so debts rise rapidly relative to incomes.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Big Debt Crisis - 9</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/reading_notes/2021/12/08/big-debt-crisis-9.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Big Debt Crisis - 9" /><published>2021-12-08T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-12-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/reading_notes/2021/12/08/big-debt-crisis-9</id><author><name></name></author><category term="investment" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">If a currency falls in relation to another currency at a rate that is greater than the currency’s interest rate, the holder of the debt in the weakening currency will lose money. If investors expect that weakness to continue without being compensated with higher interest rates, a dangerous currency dynamic will develop.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Big Debt Crisis - 8</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/reading_notes/2021/12/08/big-debt-crisis-8.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Big Debt Crisis - 8" /><published>2021-12-08T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-12-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/investment/reading_notes/2021/12/08/big-debt-crisis-8</id><author><name></name></author><category term="investment" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">Think of it this way: There are only goods and services. Financial assets are claims on them. In other words, holders of investments/assets (i.e., capitalists-investors) believe that they can convert their holdings into purchasing power to get goods and services. At the same time, workers expect to be able to exchange a unit’s worth of their contribution to the production of goods and services into buying power for goods and services. But since debt/money/ currency have no intrinsic value, the claims on them are greater than the value of what they are supposed to be able to buy, so they have to be devalued or restructured. In other words, when there are too many debt liabilities/ assets, they either have to be reduced via debt restructurings or monetized. Policy makers tend to use monetization at this stage primarily because it is stimulative rather than contractionary. But monetization simply swaps one IOU (debt) for another (newly printed money). The situation is analogous to a Ponzi scheme. Since there aren’t enough goods and services likely to be produced to back up all the IOUs, there’s a worry that people may not be willing to work in return for IOUs forever.</summary></entry></feed>