<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-06-11T17:58:08-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Evolve or Die</title><subtitle>Mainly about technology, management, ideas</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Radical Candor - 9</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/06/10/radical-candor-9.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Radical Candor - 9" /><published>2022-06-10T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-06-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/06/10/radical-candor-9</id><author><name></name></author><category term="management" /><category term="leadership" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“Scott proposed using the word “growth” instead of “potential,” to help managers think about what opportunities to give to which people on their teams. Changing one word made a world of difference. Instead of asking an implicitly judgmental question like, “Is this a person with high or low potential?” we encouraged managers to ask themselves questions like, “What growth trajectory does each person on my team want to be on right now?” or “Have I given everybody opportunities that are in line with what they really want?” or “What growth trajectory do my direct reports believe they are on? Do I agree? And if I don’t, why don’t I?” Sometimes people really want to grow and are capable of contributing more than they have been allowed to; at other times, they simply want more money or recognition but don’t really want to change the way they work or contribute any more than they do already. As the boss, you’re the one who’s going to have to know your direct reports well enough to make these distinctions and then have some Radically Candid conversations when you see things differently.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Radical Candor - 8</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/06/10/radical-candor-8.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Radical Candor - 8" /><published>2022-06-10T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-06-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/06/10/radical-candor-8</id><author><name></name></author><category term="management" /><category term="leadership" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“Karen Sipprell, a colleague at Apple, asked two questions that were instructive: “How long do you spend making sure you have all the facts right before you criticize somebody? How long do you spend making sure you have all the facts right before you praise somebody?” Ideally you’d spend just as long getting the facts right for praise as for criticism.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Radical Candor - 11</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/06/10/radical-candor-11.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Radical Candor - 11" /><published>2022-06-10T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-06-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/06/10/radical-candor-11</id><author><name></name></author><category term="management" /><category term="leadership" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“In many ways, your job as the boss is to set and uphold a quality bar. That can feel harsh in the short term, but in the long run the only thing that is meaner is lowering the bar. Don’t get sucked into Ruinous Empathy when managing people who are doing OK but not great! Everybody can excel somewhere. And to build a great team that achieves exceptional results, everybody needs to be doing great work. Accepting mediocrity isn’t good for anybody.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Radical Candor - 10</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/06/10/radical-candor-10.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Radical Candor - 10" /><published>2022-06-10T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-06-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/06/10/radical-candor-10</id><author><name></name></author><category term="management" /><category term="leadership" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“One result is described hilariously in Laurence J. Peter’s book The Peter Principle . The Peter Principle results in people getting promoted beyond their level of competence—an unhappy situation for everyone, especially the person who’s been promoted.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Radical Candor - 7</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/30/radical-candor-7.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Radical Candor - 7" /><published>2022-05-30T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-05-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/management/leadership/reading_notes/2022/05/30/radical-candor-7</id><author><name></name></author><category term="management" /><category term="leadership" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“This is an extreme example of what I call Ruinous Empathy. Ruinous Empathy is responsible for the vast majority of management mistakes I’ve seen in my career. Most people want to avoid creating tension or discomfort at work. They are like the well-meaning parent who cannot bear to discipline their kids. ”</summary></entry></feed>