<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-02-05T01:11:55-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Evolve or Die</title><subtitle>Mainly about technology, management, ideas</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Wherever you go three you are - 9</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/personal_development/reading_notes/2022/02/04/wherever-you-go-there-you-are-9.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wherever you go three you are - 9" /><published>2022-02-04T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-02-04T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/personal_development/reading_notes/2022/02/04/wherever-you-go-there-you-are-9</id><author><name></name></author><category term="personal_development" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“The trouble with this way of seeing is that it conveniently ignores the fact that you carry your head and your heart, and what some would call your “karma,” around with you. You cannot escape yourself, try as you might. And what reason, other than pure wishful thinking, would you have to suspect that things would be different or better somewhere else anyway? Sooner or later, the same problems would arise if in fact they stem in large part from your patterns of seeing, thinking, and behaving. Too often, our lives cease working because we cease working at life, because we are unwilling to take responsibility for things as they are, and to work with our difficulties. We don’t understand that it is actually possible to attain clarity, understanding, and transformation right in the middle of what is here and now, however problematic it may be. But it is easier and less threatening to our sense of self to project our involvement in our problems onto other people and the environment. It is so much easier to find fault, to blame, to believe that what is needed is a change on the outside, an escape from the forces that are holding you back, preventing you from growing, from finding happiness. You can even blame yourself for it all and, in the ultimate escape from responsibility, run away feeling that you have made a hopeless mess of things, or that you are damaged beyond repair. In either case, you believe that you are incapable of true change or growth, and that you need to spare others any more pain by removing yourself from the scene.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Wherever you go three you are - 8</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/personal_development/reading_notes/2022/01/28/wherever-you-go-there-you-are-8.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wherever you go three you are - 8" /><published>2022-01-28T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-01-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/personal_development/reading_notes/2022/01/28/wherever-you-go-there-you-are-8</id><author><name></name></author><category term="personal_development" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“Making a commitment to yourself to get up earlier than you otherwise might. Just doing it changes your life. Let that time, whatever its length, be a time of being, a time for intentional wakefulness. You don’t want to fill this time with anything other than awareness. No need to go over the day’s commitments in your head and live “ahead” of yourself. This is a time of no-time, of stillness, of presence, of being with yourself. Also, at the moment of waking up, before getting out of bed, get in touch with your breath, feel the various sensations in your body, note any thoughts and feelings that may be present, let mindfulness touch this moment. Can you feel your breathing? Can you perceive the dawning of each in breath? Can you enjoy the feeling of the breath freely entering your body in this moment? Ask yourself: “Am I awake now?”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Wherever you go there you are - 7</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/personal_development/reading_notes/2022/01/28/wherever-you-go-there-you-are-7.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wherever you go there you are - 7" /><published>2022-01-28T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-01-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/personal_development/reading_notes/2022/01/28/wherever-you-go-there-you-are-7</id><author><name></name></author><category term="personal_development" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“Contemplating “What is my Way?” is an excellent element to inject into our meditation practice. We don’t have to come up with answers, nor think that there has to be one particular answer. Better not to think at all. Instead, only persist in asking the question, letting any answers that formulate just come of themselves and go of themselves. As with everything else in the meditation practice, we just watch, listen, note, let be, let go, and keep generating the question, “What is my Way?”, “What is my path?”, “Who am I?”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Wherever you go there you are - 6</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/personal_development/reading_notes/2022/01/23/wherever-you-go-there-you-are-6.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wherever you go there you are - 6" /><published>2022-01-23T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-01-23T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/personal_development/reading_notes/2022/01/23/wherever-you-go-there-you-are-6</id><author><name></name></author><category term="personal_development" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“Siddhartha listened. He was now listening intently, completely absorbed, quite empty, taking in everything. He felt that he had now completely learned the art of listening. He had often heard all this before, all these numerous voices in the river, but today they sounded different. He could no longer distinguish the different voices—the merry voice from the weeping voice, the childish voice from the manly voice. They all belonged to each other: the lament of those who yearn, the laughter of the wise, the cry of indignation and the groan of the dying. They were all interwoven and interlocked, entwined in a thousand ways. And all the voices, all the goals, all the pleasures, all the good and evil, all of them together was the world. All of them together was the stream of events, the music of life. When Siddhartha listened attentively to this river, to this song of a thousand voices, when he did not listen to the sorrow or the laughter, when he did not bind his soul to any one particular voice and absorb it in his Self, but heard them all, the whole, the unity, then the great song of a thousand voices consisted of one word.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Wherever you go three you are - 5</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/personal_development/reading_notes/2022/01/17/wherever-you-go-there-you-are-5.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wherever you go three you are - 5" /><published>2022-01-17T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-01-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/personal_development/reading_notes/2022/01/17/wherever-you-go-there-you-are-5</id><author><name></name></author><category term="personal_development" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“Awareness is not the same as thought. It lies beyond thinking, although it makes use of thinking, honoring its value and its power. Awareness is more like a vessel which can hold and contain our thinking, helping us to see and know our thoughts as thoughts rather than getting caught up in them as reality.”</summary></entry></feed>