<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-07-24T13:09:26-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Evolve or Die</title><subtitle>Mainly about technology, management, ideas</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Angel - How to invest in technology startups (Chapter 11 - 12)</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/angel_investing/investment/reading_notes/2021/07/24/angel-investing-syndicate-11-12.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Angel - How to invest in technology startups (Chapter 11 - 12)" /><published>2021-07-24T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-07-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/angel_investing/investment/reading_notes/2021/07/24/angel-investing-syndicate-11-12</id><author><name></name></author><category term="angel_investing" /><category term="investment" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">Chapter 11: 天使联合会 (Angel Syndicate) At these sites, successful angel investors create an investment group, or syndicate, where they explain what they typically invest in, what they’ve already invested in (their track record), how much they typically invest per deal (typically $10,000 to $100,000), and how much in “carry” they will charge you on a successful exit. Carry is short for “carried interest,” and it’s defined as the share of profits that go to the fund manager—in this case called the syndicate lead. On these platforms, the syndicate leads typically take a 15 percent carry and the platform itself takes another 5 percent, for a total of a 20 percent carry. This is exactly how venture capital firms charge their own investors, who are called limited partners (LPs), with one critical difference: fees. With angel syndicates, you simply pay the carry. There are no fees other than some minor legal and filing fees (typically less than $10,000 per deal, spread out across the dozens of investors in a deal). Individual angels like you can sign up for a syndicate (like mine) and make a nonbinding pledge to invest a small dollar amount per deal. On my syndicate, the minimum is $1,000, but most syndicates set this number at $2,500 to weed out the more casual investors. When a syndicate lead shares a deal, each of the syndicate members gets a chance to evaluate the deal via an online profile for that startup that typically includes a pitch deck and why the syndicate lead is investing. A syndicate normally negotiates an allocation with the founder of the startup, typically $200,000 to $500,000 (or 10 to 50 percent of a seed round). If the syndicate can pull together enough investment interest, the deal is consummated. That’s why I advocate that new angels do ten small angel syndicates before they start doing direct investing. Beyond the very real chance of getting a positive return on your investment, if you do this hack, you will build your reputation, have a chance to prove your worth to founders, and jump-start your network—all for the bargain price of $25,000. That’s only 20 percent of the cost of an MBA and you can do it in a month! Syndicates require very little paperwork and you can choose to invest without taking any meetings or doing any due diligence. The only thing you need be able to do is prove that you’re an accredited investor here in the United States and have your wire transfer clear.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Angel - How to invest in technology startups (Chapter 1 - 10)</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/angel_investing/investment/reading_notes/2021/07/23/angel-investment-jason-calacanis-1-10.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Angel - How to invest in technology startups (Chapter 1 - 10)" /><published>2021-07-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-07-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/angel_investing/investment/reading_notes/2021/07/23/angel-investment-jason-calacanis-1-10</id><author><name></name></author><category term="angel_investing" /><category term="investment" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">Chapter 1: 技术进步无可避免 But I don’t invest in this future because I want to sit in an ivory tower laughing at people whose jobs are replaced. I invest in this future because it’s inevitable and I think I can help accelerate the efforts of the founders and innovators who are missionaries, not mercenaries. Of course, I plan to make a great deal of money in these revolutions, but I also plan to look back proudly and know that I helped propel changes that made our planet better.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Leadership Pipeline - Coaching</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/leadership/reading_notes/2021/07/19/the-leadership-pipeline-coaching.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Leadership Pipeline - Coaching" /><published>2021-07-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-07-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/leadership/reading_notes/2021/07/19/the-leadership-pipeline-coaching</id><author><name></name></author><category term="leadership" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">Three-question framework Question 1 Tell me about your career - your jobs, the work you did, achievements, key challenges, and learning.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Leadership Pipeline - comfortable zone and job definition</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/leadership/reading_notes/2021/07/17/the-leadership-pipeline-comfort-zone.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Leadership Pipeline - comfortable zone and job definition" /><published>2021-07-17T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-07-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/leadership/reading_notes/2021/07/17/the-leadership-pipeline-comfort-zone</id><author><name></name></author><category term="leadership" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">“When managers begin to replicate behaviors almost identical to those that brought them an earlier success, a warning bell should go off.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Leadership Pipeline - Facebook IC view</title><link href="https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/leadership/reading_notes/2021/07/11/the-leadership-pipeline-fb-ic.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Leadership Pipeline - Facebook IC view" /><published>2021-07-11T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-07-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://taihangye.github.io/evolve-or-die/leadership/reading_notes/2021/07/11/the-leadership-pipeline-fb-ic</id><author><name></name></author><category term="leadership" /><category term="reading_notes" /><summary type="html">General Requirements for Two Adjacent Levels May Be Similar, But Specific Skills, Time Applications, and Work Values Reveal Significant Differences. Generating Results at One Level Should Not Be the Main Reason to Select Someone for a Higher-Level Position.</summary></entry></feed>